

DEBANJAN SAMANTA SENIOR SYSTEMS ENGINEER

+91-8017236758

Behala, Kolkata, West Bengal,

samanta.debanjan2020@gmail.com

Experienced (3+ years) Software Developer having expertise in developing, installing, testing and maintaining software systems. I'm an enthusiastic, responsible and hard working IT person. Working for different projects and teams helped me adapt to changes quickly and made me a mature team player. I am able to perform well both in a team as well as on my own in any initiative. Known to manage strict deadlines and also work under pressure. I posses trouble shooting skills to analyze code and engineer optimal solutions for the same.

DOMAIN/TECHNICAL EXPERTISE:

 $\textbf{Technologies:} \ \mathsf{Java/J2EE}, \ \mathsf{Python} \ , \ \mathsf{SQL}, \ \mathsf{HTML5}, \ \mathsf{Spring} \ \mathsf{Boot}, \ \mathsf{CSS3}, \ \mathsf{JavaScript}, \ \mathsf{Unix}, \\$

REDIS, Angular, Google Associate Cloud Engineer. **IDEs:** Eclipse, Visual Studio, Sprint Tool Suite

Database: PLSQL(Oracle)

Operating System: Windows, LINUX

Methodologies: Agile(Scrums & Sprints), Kanban

Tools: JIRA, UC4, SAM Portal Oracle, SoapUI, CVS, PUTTY, HP-ALM, GIIT, IBM DataStage

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

NEOTIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY MANAGEMENT AND SCIENCE

COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING (CSE), BATCH OF 2014-18

- Graduated with Bachelor of Technology
- Graduate for programming & development
- Worked as Class Representative.

NATIONAL GEMS HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL (2000-14)

COMPUTER SCIENCE APPLICATIONS, BATCH OF 2012-14

- Indian School Certificate(ISC-12th): 74%
- Indian Certificate of Secondary Education(ICSE-10th): 85.43%

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

SENIOR SYSTEMS ENGINEER

INFOSYS | JUN 2020 - PRESENT

- Developed optimized quality code using all best practices
- Involved in development, testing, review, delivery.
- Defect tracking, monitoring and problem solving.
- Managed team when team lead was unavailable.
- Involved in Production Support for release go live to monitor defects and resolution.
- Certified as Google Associate Cloud Engineer.

SYSTEMS ENGINEER

INFOSYS | JUL 2018 - JUN 2020

- Trained for Fundamentals of Python, RDBMS and Certified as Java (J2EE) Full Stack Developer.
- Familiar with in sprint activities and events tollowed for a sprint
- Took part in account level initiatives including innovation and migration of system data.
- Involved in account level extra curricular activities for event management and guidance.

KEY STRENGTHS& INTERESTS:

- Pro-active
- Communication
- Flexible
- Quick Learning
- Team Work

- Video & still photography
- Gaming
- Travel Riding
- Volunteering
- Cooking